In the State of Qin and the State of Wei's fierce battle, Xin and Lun Hu have faced off once again.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）秦国(しんこく)と魏国(ぎこく)との
激戦の中で 再び対峙(たいじ)した信(しん)と輪虎(りんこ)
Which will be the one to surpass their limits and continue on their path?
限界を超え 己の道を貫き通すのは
果たして どちらか
２人の熱き思いが今 火花を散らす
These two's heated emotions are now making sparks fly.
He can't... get up anymore.
（信）こいつは もう―
立ち上がれねえ
立ち上がれるはず… が…
There's no way he... can...
Lun Hu. You bastard...
輪虎 てめえ…
My lord is... waiting.
（輪虎）殿が… 待っている
I cannot... lose here.
こんな所で負けられない
Precious Comrades
I cannot lose.
僕は負けられない
I was sent by the heavens to be Lian Po's sword.
僕は 天の与えし廉頗(れんぱ)の剣(つるぎ)だからね
天？
The heavens?
There is only a handful of military commanders loved by the heavens.
（輪虎）天に愛される武将は
ほんの ひと握り
（輪虎）運命だった
It was fate.
あのとき 死にかけていた僕が
殿に拾われたのは―
My being picked up by my lord when I was on the verge of death...
天の計らいだった
was arranged by heaven.
Picked up? By Lian Po?!
拾われた？ 廉頗に？
（輪虎）
最初は ごく ありふれた話さ
It started out as a very common story.
戦渦に巻き込まれた小さな村
A small village caught up in a war.
All of the villagers died, and while my sister and I just managed to survive.
村人は皆 死に―
かろうじて生き残った幼い僕と妹も
ただ 飢え死にの時を待っていた
Still being small children, all we could do was wait to die of starvation.
I don't know how many days had passed when...
それから 何日たったか分からない
（輪虎）僕は あの人に会った
I met that man.
There are some child survivors
（廉頗）小僧が生き残っておる
水と食べ物を与えてやれ
Give them some food and water.
Yes, sir.
Th-Thank you...
あ… ありがたく…
しかし
ぼ… 僕の前に どうか妹に…
B-But please, before me, help my sister...
（廉頗）それはムリじゃ
（輪虎）えっ？
I'm afraid we can't.
I'm ashamed to say, I hadn't noticed.
（輪虎）情けないことに
僕は気づいていなかった
My little sister was already long dead.
妹が とっくに死んでいたことに
ハハッ… 妹の話は関係なかったか
Though I guess the part about my little sister isn't important.
とにかく 僕は命を救われた
Anyhow, my life was saved.
By the Great General, Lian Po!
あの大将軍 廉頗に
偶然だと思うかい？
Do you think that was a coincidence?
結果的に
戦いの才能があった僕と 廉頗
It resulted in me, the fighting genius, fighting alongside Lian Po.
戦いの天才が
戦いの大天才に拾われたことを
The fighting genius being adopted by the great fighting genius.
玄峰(げんぽう)さまが よく言っていたよ
Lord Xuan Feng used to say this quite often.
“天に愛される武将は
ほんの ひと握り”
"There is only a handful of military commanders loved by the heavens."
“そのひとりである廉頗に 天が
出会わせた剣が この僕だ”ってね
And one of those, Lian Po,
has me, the sword that the heavens guided to him.
だから 僕は…
That's why I...
That's why I can't die in a place like thi—
だから 僕は
こんな所で負けるわけに…
Bullshit!
（信）くだらねえ！
From what you've been saying,
さっきから聞いてりゃ…
you're making it all sound like this is all something that's in the hands of the heavens.
それじゃ まるで
全部 天任せみてえじゃねえか
そうじゃねえだろう！
But it's not!
We're all standing and fighting on our own legs!
俺たちは みんな
てめえの足で立って戦ってんだ！
Even you are putting your life on the line to fight as Lian Po's sword, right?!
今のお前だって―
廉頗の剣であるために 命懸けで
戦いまくってきた結果だろうが！
だけど
出会いが重要だってことは分かる
Still, I know how important chance encounters are.
Like how you met Lian Po,
お前が廉頗に出会ったってんなら
俺だって―
I met with a man who should've become a general even greater than Lian Po.
廉頗以上の大将軍に
なるはずだった男に出会い
And I grew up with him.
そいつと共に育った
（慶(けい)）尾平(びへい)…
（尾平）ああ
Wei Ping.
Yeah!
Piao...!
He gave me my dream... and died way too soon.
俺に夢をくれた そいつは
はやばやと死んじまったが
And in his place... I met another out-of-this-world person.
代わりに―
俺は また
とんでもねえヤツと出会った
それから掛けがえのねえ戦友たちと
出会い 別れ
Since then, I met with and said goodbye to lots of comrades in arms...
and I even met a person that would become a realistic guideline for my path.
そして 俺の道の
現実的な指針となる人にも会った
それが偶然じゃねえっていうなら
そうかもしんねえが
You could say that those weren't coincidences,
but I know it wasn't some flighty thing like the heavens or whatever!
天とか何とか
浮ついたことは考えねえ！
I just moved forward, carrying the thoughts of those I encountered!
俺は 関わったヤツらの
思いをしょって 前に進むだけだ
輪虎！ お前と戦ったことも
でっけえ糧にしてな
Lun Hu, fighting you will be great fuel for me, too!
ハハッ… 言うねえ
That's what you say.
でも 死ぬのは君だから
But you're the one who's going to die.
（輪虎）信 君の言うとおり―
Xin, what you said is correct.
Meetings are fate, and everything past that depends on you.
出会いは運命で
そこから先は自分しだいさ
ただし
天の起こす奇跡も 必ずあるけどね
But there are definitely miracles brought about by the heavens...
My lord...
殿…
王騎(おうき)が死に
With the death of Wang Qi and the appearance of the great force that is Li Mu,
李牧(りぼく)という大物が現れ
秦国軍にも
若き力が芽吹こうとしている
even the State of Qin is trying to sprout some new talent.
時代は やはり
次の戦乱の世へ移ろうとしています
The era is shifting to the next world of wars.
ひょっとしたら 殿が亡命して
前線から退いた あのとき
Perhaps when my lord fled his country and left the front lines...
my duty was complete.
僕の役目は
終わっていたのかもしれませんね…
Even if that is the case, perhaps my fighting here
それでも―
今ここで戦っているのは…
was arranged by the heavens as well?
これもまた 天の計らいか
なかなか強かったよ 飛信(ひしん)隊 信
You were quite strong, Xin of the Feixin Unit.
信…
Xin... you... also...
君も また…
Lun Hu. You were an incredible opponent that made me prepare myself to die many times.
輪虎
お前は 何度も死を覚悟したくれえ
ヤバイ相手だったぜ
（慶）やった！ やったぞ！
He did it! He really did it!
He beat Lun Hu!
輪虎を倒した！
廉頗四天王の輪虎を倒した！
He beat one of Lian Po's Four Heavenly Kings, Lun Hu!
And now...
（竜有(りゅうゆう)）しかも これで！
（田永(でんえい)）ああ
Yeah!
条件だった将軍の首１つを
成し遂げたぜ バカ野郎！
We've fulfilled our condition of taking the head of a general, goddammit!
（番陽(ばんよう)）ンンッ…
賁(ほん)さま あれは！
Lord Ben, over there!
（刺す音）
（魏兵）ウワッ！
I hear it.
（王賁(おうほん)）聞こえている
（輪虎兵）輪虎さま！
（輪虎兵）くそ！
Lord Lun Hu!
Dammit!
（兵士）ウワッ！
（兵士）敵が！ 輪虎兵が！
Enemies!
The Lun Hu soldiers!
Leave them to us!
（元郭備(かくび)兵）ヤツらは任せよ！
（元郭備兵）元郭備兵として
堂々と引導を渡してやる！
As former Guo Bei soldiers, it's our job to put an end to them!
信！ さっさと そいつの首をはねろ
Xin! Hurry up and cut off that guy's head!
We're to hold it up and let the whole battlefield know!
掲げて回って
戦場中に知らしめるんだ
（信）輪虎…
Lun Hu...
（渕(えん)）信どの…
Lord Xin...
（渕）首を持って回らずとも
事実は ちゃんと広まる！
Even without the head, the word will still spread!
飛信隊隊長の信が
敵将 輪虎を討ち取ったと―
Pass along that Xin, the captain of the Feixin Unit has killed the enemy general, Lun Hu!
触れて回るんだ！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
（渕）楚水(そすい)副長の具合は？
How is Vice Captain Chu Shui?!
Somehow, he hasn't suffered any fatal wounds!
（元郭備兵）
なんとか致命傷には至っていません
I think we can save him if we stop the bleeding!
出血さえ止まれば 助かります
（渕）よし
Good!
（昂(こう)）尾平さん…
（尾平）ああ
Mr. Wei Ping.
Yeah.
とりあえず 俺らのほうは
全部 うまくいったみてえだ
For now, it looked like everything went well for us.
（去亥(きょがい)）あっ…
うん？ どうかしたか？ 竜川(りゅうせん)
Is something wrong, Long Chuan?
Something's... kinda weird.
（竜川）ちょっと変なんだ…
I can't see any sign of people in the area where we left Vice Captain Qiang Lei and the others.
羌瘣(きょうかい)副長たちを残してきた辺り一帯
人影が全くない
これで終わったと思っているのか？
めでたいヤツらめ
Do you think it's over, you joyous bastards?!
General Lun Hu placed a separate reserve unit next to this main army.
輪虎将軍は この本軍の横に
別動の予備隊を置いていた
お前らが ここに集中したとき
手薄になった所に突撃するようにな
So the moment you gathered here
he could have them charge on the undermanned areas!
な… なんだと！
Wh-What?!
So if you left comrades there,
そこに仲間を置いてきたってんなら
今ごろ１人残らず踏み殺されてるぜ
you can bet that every last one of them's been trampled to death!
ハハハッ… 何せ 別動隊は―
That separate unit was made up of 500 men from the army of the head of the Four Heavenly Kings, General Jie Zifang!
あの四天王筆頭 介子坊(かいしぼう)将軍の
私兵500だからな ハハハハッ！
ふ… ふざけたこと
言ってんじゃねえぞ こら！
Q-Quit spouting bullshit, you bastard!
Long Chuan, search carefully!
竜川！ ちゃんと捜せよ
マジで見えねえのか？
Can you seriously not see them anywhere?!
こ… この雨だし ここからじゃ…
I-In this rain, it's pretty hard to see from...
（沛浪(はいろう)）あっ… 信！
Xin!
（松左(しょうさ)）お… 俺たちも行くぞ！
（兵士たち）おう！
Let's go, too!
侵略者どもが… いい気味だ…
Serves you invaders right...
Qiang Lei, I'll see you later.
Right.
（信）羌瘣
また あとでな
Qiang Lei!
Qiang Lei
羌瘣ーっ！
This was approximately one hour before Xin struck down Lun Hu.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）それは 信が輪虎を
討ち取る１時間ほど前のことである
後方に残ったのは
羌瘣と負傷兵 およそ200名
Qiang Lei was left behind with approximately 200 wounded soldiers.
What's happening with the captain and the others?
（負傷兵Ａ）
隊長たちは どうなってる？
（負傷兵Ｂ）
輪虎と一騎打ちやってるみたいだが
It looks like he's going one-on-one with Lun Hu...
but it's hard to tell much from here.
ここからじゃ よく分からん
（鬨(とき)の声）
ハッ…
（兵士たち）ウワーッ！
何だ？ あれは
What... is that...?
（負傷兵Ａ）
て… 敵の新手か？
A new batch of enemies!
（負傷兵Ｂ）
で… でかい！
It-It's huge!
Foot soldiers are flying this way like a spear!
歩兵が棒きれみたいに
吹き飛んでる
（兵士）く… 来るぞ！
I-Incoming!
What are you doing, reserve unit?!
（兵士）何やってる 予備隊！
早く応援に来い！
Come here and back us up, quickly!
急げ！
（負傷兵Ｃ）あ… あんなの
俺たちが行っても止められっこねえ
W-We can't stop an enemy like that!
You idiot, what do you think you're saying?!
（負傷兵Ｄ）
バカ野郎 何言ってんだ
We're a reserve unit put in place precisely for situations like this!
こういう事態のための
予備隊だろうが
B-But...
（負傷兵Ｃ）で… でも…
Let's go!
行くぞ！
（負傷兵Ｃ）お… おう
We shouldn't go.
行くべきじゃない…
この戦力と 今の自分では―
As we are now...
we cannot stop a force like that.
あれは止められない
早く来てくれ 飛信隊！
Hurry, get moving, Feixin Unit!
副長！
（負傷兵）羌瘣副長！
Vice Captain!
Vice Captain Qiang Lei!
（負傷兵たち）副長！
Vice Captain...
Big Sis Xiang...
象(しょう)姉…
死ねば 象姉の敵(かたき)は討てなくなる
If I die... I'll never be able to avenge Big Sis Xiang.
If we go, we'll just be running to our deaths!
行っても
ただ 死にに行くようなもんだ！
やめたほうが…
（負傷兵Ｅ）ふざけるな 貴様！
We should just...
Shut your mouth, you bastard!
それでも飛信隊か！
You call yourself a member of the Feixin Unit?!
隊長たちだって今
命懸けで戦ってんだぞ！
Our captain and the others are out there risking their lives right now!
I'm sorry, Big Sis Xiang.
ごめん 象姉
Right now... I am a vice captain of the Feixin Unit!
やっぱり今は 私は飛信隊の副長だ
行くぞ！
（負傷兵たち）オーッ！
Let's go!
Damn. Am I really this much of an idiot?
くそ…
私って こんなバカだったか？
Be careful, Lei.
（象）気をつけるんだぞ 瘣
バカのそばにいると バカが うつる
If you stick close to idiots, their stupidity will spread to you.
（羌瘣）フッ… それだ
That must be it.
Vice General Qiang Lei...
（負傷兵Ａ）羌瘣副長が―
笑ってる？
is smiling?
（斬る音）
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
They're all... dead.
（尾平）みんな… 死んでる
（田永）くそ…
Shit. Where are Vice Captain Qiang Lei and the others?!
羌瘣副長たちは どこだ？
（去亥）隊長！
（信）ハッ…
Captain!
こいつ まだ息がある
俺の什(じゅう)のヤツだ
This guy is still alive!
He's from our Shen!
おい 何があった？
Hey, what happened?!
I... I'm sorry.
（太関）す… すいやせん
敵が強すぎて 俺ら 何も…
The enemy was... too strong...
We couldn't do anything...
But... Vice Captain Qiang Lei...
なのに 羌瘣副長は―
ただでさえ苦しそうだったのに
たった１人で…
Even though he wasn't in great shape to being with... he fought alone...
羌瘣が？
Qiang Lei...
I'm so sorry. We were really useless...
すいやせん…
俺ら ホントに役立たずで…
They were too strong... The vice captain... The vice captain...
ヤツら あまりに すごくて…
副長が…
（羌瘣）ここが今の私にとって―
This is the only place I can call home now.
唯一の帰る場所だからだ
So when this war is over, I'm leaving here.
だから この戦が終わったら―
私は ここを出ていく
I don't know how many months or years it'll take...
何か月…
何年かかるか分からないけど
but I'll make sure I get my revenge.
きっちり敵を討つ
そして それが終わって
また帰ってきたら…
And when that's done, if I come back again...
Bullshit...
（信）ざけんな… ざけんなよ 羌瘣
Quit screwing around, Qiang Lei!
When that happens, I think I'll really be able to move forward with all of you.
（羌瘣）そのときは―
私も ちゃんと
お前たちと一緒に前に進めると思う
What are you doing, you fucking idiot?!
何やってんだ この大バカ野郎が…
羌瘣！
Qiang Lei!
この辺 すげえ でけえのばっかり…
これが介子坊の私兵か？
Everyone around here is huge.
Are these Jie Zinfang's men?
They're all torn to shreds.
（尾平）
全員 ズタボロだ… 何だ？ こりゃ
What happened here?
Th... That was no human.
（介子坊兵）ひ… 人じゃねえ
（尾平･慶）ハッ…
あ… あれは人じゃねえ…
That... was not a human...
なんだ…
Huh? You...?
お前か…
羌瘣！
Qiang Lei!
バカか お前は！
こんなんなるまでムチャしやがって
Are you an idiot?!
How could you be so reckless that you'd end up like this?!
死んじまったら
姉ちゃんの敵討ちもできねえんだぞ
You can't avenge your sister if you die!
ひどいな… 私なりに頑張ったのに
What an awful thing to say...
After I fought so hard like that...
そっちは… 終わったのか？
Did you... finish?
Yeah. I took down Lun Hu just like I said I would.
ああ きっちり輪虎を討ち取ったぞ
（羌瘣）そうか…
I see.
信…
（信）うん？
Xin.
離せ… バカが うつる
（信）うるせえよ！
Let me go.
Your stupidity is spreading.
Shut up!
（兵士）
羌瘣副長が無事って 本当か？
Is Vice Captain Qiang Lei really okay?!
ああ こっちだ！
Yeah. They're this way.
Did the vice captain really beat all these huge guys on his own?
（昂）このでかいヤツら
全部 副長１人で？
This is superhuman...
（兵士）人間業じゃねえな…
（昂）うん？ あっ いた！
There they are!
（兵士）
什長たち 集まって何してんだ？
The Shen Chiefs are all gathered together. What's going on?!
No way...
（田永）そんな…
（渕）バカな…
How can that...
Q-Qiang Lei is a woman?!
きょ… 羌瘣って―
女だったのか？
どういうことだ？ 信
What's going on here, Xin?!
Don't tell me you knew that Qiang Lei was a woman the whole time?!
羌瘣が女って…
まさか お前 知ってたのか？
（田永）なに黙ってんだ お前！
Why didn't you say anything?!
（尾平）いつから知ってた？
（去亥）ちゃんと説明しろ！
How long have you known this?!
We want an explanation!
（田有(でんゆう)）
ピーピーうるせえぞ お前ら
Quit squealing, you guys.
Just how many lives has Qiang Lei saved up until now?
（田有）今まで 羌瘣に
どれだけ命を救われてきた？
It doesn't matter if she's a woman or not at this point.
今更 女だろうが何だろうが
関係ねえだろう
Think about it a bit.
少しは察してやれや
女の身で
あんだけの剣技を身に着けて―
To learn swordplay like that as a woman, then blend in with men on the battlefield...
男に交じって戦場に来てるってのは
よっぽど でけえ何かを
しょってんだろうってな
she must be carrying quite a burden.
You've got it backwards, Tian You.
（信）逆だ 田有
（兵士たち）えっ？
She's actually really "empty".
逆に こいつは空っぽなんだ
There was this horrible law in the place she grew up.
こいつの育った場所には
ひでえ掟(おきて)があってよ
その掟の中で こいつは
幼なじみの姉ちゃんのために―
And because of those, she was planning on dying for the sake of her older sister.
死ぬつもりだったらしい
（尾平）えっ…
だけど 結果的に 姉ちゃんは殺され
自分が生き残っちまった
But in the end, her big sister ended up being killed, and she was the one left alive.
Ever since then, she's been traveling to avenge her sister.
以来 こいつは
姉ちゃんの敵討ちの旅をしている
That's everything for her.
こいつにとっては それが全てだ
生きる目標は
敵討ちしかなかったんだ
Her only goal in life was to get revenge.
It's possible...
ひょっとしたら
こいつは 敵討ちが終わったら―
she was just going to kill herself after she got revenge.
そこで
死ぬつもりだったのかもしれねえ
But...
だけど 最近 こいつは
少しずつ変わろうとしている
recently, she's been trying to change.
敵討ち以外に…
She's been thinking about things besides revenge... about what she wants to do after...
敵討ちの先にも 生きる場所が
ようやく見つかろうとしているんだ
and about finding a place to live.
And that's the Feixin Unit.
それが飛信隊だ
I'm not gonna ask you guys to pretend you didn't notice this...
今更 気づかなかったフリを
しろとは言わねえが
今までどおり
接してくれねえか？ みんな
but could you keep treating her like you always have, guys?
She's... one of our precious comrades.
こいつは
俺らの大事な仲間なんだからよ
It's all right, Lord Xin.
大丈夫ですよ 信どの
田有の言ったとおり
羌瘣どのは羌瘣どのです
Just as Tian You said, Lord Qiang Lei is Lord Qiang Lei.
It will be just the same as it has always...
今までどおり変わりなく…
（尾平）今までどおりじゃダメだ！
It can't be the same as always!
Wei Ping...
（渕）尾平…
女ってのは
絶対 この先 いつか敵にもバレる
It's definitely eventually gonna leak to the enemy that she's a woman!
そしたら 羌瘣を狙うヤツらも
出てくるだろうし
When that happens, there're definitely gonna be people that'll target her!
捕まれば
ひでえ目に遭わされるに違いねえ
And you can bet that some horrible things'll happen to her if they capture her!
そうならねえように これからは…
So to make sure that doesn't happen, from now on...
羌瘣の強さに比べりゃ
屁(へ)みてえな俺らだが…
Even though our strength is nothing compared to Qiang Lei's...
みんなで 少しずつ―
Little by little, we've all got to become able to protect Qiang Lei together!
羌瘣を守っていってやんなきゃ
ならねえんだ！
まあ そういうことだな
Well, he's got a point.
ケッ…
尾平のくせに まともなことを
Wei Ping actually said something pretty decent.
Hey, you're the one getting rescued by her more often than anyone!
…て お前が いちばん
助けられまくってんだろうが
（尾平）あっ…
（竜有）カッコつけやがって
Quit tryin' ta act cool.
Sh-Shut up!
（尾平）なっ… うるせえ！
（笑い声）
Better get stronger, Wei Ping.
強くなれよ 尾平
（尾平）うるせえっつってんだろう
I said shut up!
良かったな 羌瘣
You must be glad, Qiang Lei.
Okay, how about us old geezers take care of treating Qiang Lei?
（魯延(ろえん)）
それじゃ 羌瘣副長の手当ては―
老いぼれたちが引き受けようかのぅ
（信）頼む 魯延じい
Thanks, Old Man Lu Yan.
Xin, you've gotta get fixed up, too.
（尾平）信 お前も手当てしねえと
Right...
ああ… いてっ…
（尾平）立てるか？
Ow...
Can you stand?
手当ては 脚の止血だけでいい
それより 馬を持ってきてくれ
Just stop my leg from bleeding, that's enough.
Somebody, go bring a horse.
（尾平･慶）えっ？
（信）渕さん
Mr. Yuan, how is the enemy army looking?
敵軍の様子は？
（渕）はい
Yes, sir. They've lost morale after hearing of Lun Hu's death,
輪虎討ち死にの報により
勢いは失いましたが
but they haven't been completely routed.
総崩れというわけでもありません
やはり 輪虎が生っ粋の
魏国将軍ではなかったことと―
I suppose due to the fact that Lun Hu was not purely a State of Wei general
侵略される側の士気は
たやすく折れぬということでしょう
their morale raised from being invaded won't easily be broken.
優勢ではあるんだな？
（渕）今のところ
So they have the advantage?
As of now.
（信）
渕さん 悪い　ここ任せていいか？
Sorry, Mr. Yuan, could I leave this place to you?
Lord Xin, you don't mean...
信どの まさか…
Yeah.
最後に まだ行く所があるんだ
I still have... one last place to go.
Preview
Meng Ao, Standing Firm
End